historycentral.com 2010-11-24

# HistoryCentral.com: Privacy Policy

HistoryCentral.com

_**STATEMENT REGARDING INFORMAITON USE & PRIVACY ON THIS SITE**_

MultiEducator Incorporated  
244 North Avenue  
New Rochelle, NY 10801

We created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for HistoryCentral.com, which is wholly owned and operated by MultiEducator, Inc.

**Information Automatically Logged**

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and your shopping cart.

**Cookies**

Some pages on our site may use "cookies" to keep track of your shopping cart. Cookies are small data files stored on a user’s computer, which keep track of various information. Cookies on HistoryCentral.com are used primarily to deliver advertisements.

**Advertisers**

At historycentral.com, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit historycentral. com, and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties.  
Log Files  
As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.  
Cookies and Web Beacons  
We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.  
We also use third party advertisements on historycentral.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).  
DoubleClick DART cookies  
We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through GoogleÃ­s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (Ã®interest based targetingÃ®). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses Ã¬non personally identifiable informationÃ®. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting? <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx>  
You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.  
Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

We use additional third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

**Registration Forms**

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (such as their name, email, and postal address), unique identifiers (like their social security number), and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level).

Contact information from the registration forms is used to ship purchases, information about our company. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the customer if and when it becomes necessary.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

Demographic and profile data is occasionally collected at our site. Your data will never be sold, given, or otherwise transmitted to any third parties.

**Order Forms**

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products and services. We collect contact information (like their email address), financial information (like their account or credit card numbers) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level).

Contact information from the order forms is used to ship purchases and information about our company, should the user opt to receive such materials. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary, and to ship products ordered via the Web site.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

Credit card numbers and other related information that is collected are used to bill the user for products and services.

Unique identifiers (such as social security numbers) are collected from Web site visitors to verify the user's identity, and for use as account numbers in our record system.

**Surveys**

Our online surveys may ask visitors for contact information (like email address) and demographic information (like zip code, age, or income level). This information is used for statistical purposes only, unless the user indicates that he or she would like to be added to our mailing list.

Contact information from the surveys is used to ship purchases and information about our company. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

**External Links**

This site contains links to other sites. Neither MultiEducator nor HistoryCentral.com is responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

**Special Relationships**

Some links may be referenced to outside sites, through which you may order their products and services. Wherever you see "powered by" or "affiliate," please be aware that those sites operate under different privacy guidelines and their practices are not under our control.

**Public Forums**

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving promotional/marketing information from us.

1\. You can send email to webmaster@multied.com

2\. You can send mail to the following postal address:

MultiEducator, Inc.  
HistoryCentral.com  
226 North Avenue  
New Rochelle, NY 10801

**Data Quality/Access**

HistoryCentral.com gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided; they may send email to webmaster@multied.com.

**Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact us at [mutied@multied.com](mailto:mutied@multied.com), or use the postal address above.
